Guide to the Stanford Channel Records
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Stanford Channel records
1983-2001
1995-2001
SC0763
Stanford Channel (Television station: Stanford, Calif.)
2.5 Linear feet
Records consist primarily of booking files for programs, which include correspondence, schedules, notes, and materials related to the event or subject of programs. There are also a few administrative files pertaining to funding and an evaluation done in 1998.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Information about Access
This collection is open for research.
Biographical/Historical Sketch
Stanford Channel, the university's educational cable television channel, debuted in 1995 as Channel 51; it ceased operations in October 2001. When it began in 1995, it was one of the few cable broadcast outlets in the nation owned and operated by a private university. Its programs included university events, lectures, arts programming and sports.
Description of the Collection
Records consist primarily of booking files for programs, which include correspondence, schedules, notes, and materials related to the event or subject of programs. There are also a few administrative files pertaining to funding and an evaluation done in 1998.
Access Terms
Stanford Channel (Television station: Stanford, Calif.); Stanford Channel (Television station: Stanford, Calif.); Educational television programs.; Television broadcasting--California.
Collection Contents
- Records, Accession ARCH-2005-197
  - ACT Report 1998 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Evaluation 1998 (1) [includes Channel 51 Baseline Survey 1995] (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Evaluation 1998 (2) [includes Report to the CTTL on the Stanford Channel, 1998, and The Stanford Channel Business Plan, 1998] (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Evaluation 1998 (3) [includes "How video can enhance the basic mission of the University: excellence in teaching and research" by Mary Lou Allen 1984 and results of a video survey at Stanford August 1983] (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Humanities and Sciences – underwriting (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Lively Arts, 1997-2000 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - ResearchTV (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - TSC – underwriting 1999-2001 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Booking sheets 1996-1999 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Booking file, spring 1995 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Booking file, fall 1995 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Booking file, winter 1996 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Booking file, spring 1996 (1) (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Booking file, spring 1996 (2) (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Booking file, summer 1996 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Booking file, fall 1996 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Booking file, fall 1996 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Booking file, winter 1997 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Booking file, spring 1997 (1) (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Booking file, spring 1997 (2) (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Booking file, summer 1997 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Booking file, fall 1997 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Booking file, winter 1998 (1) (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Booking file, winter 1998 (2) (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Booking file, spring 1998 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Booking file, summer 1998 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Booking file, fall 1998 (1) (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Booking file, fall 1998 (2) (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Booking file, winter 1999 (1) (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Booking file, winter 1999 (2) (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Booking file, spring 1999 (1) (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Booking file, spring 1999 (2) (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Booking file, summer 1999 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Booking file, fall 1999 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Booking file, winter 2000 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Booking file, spring 2000 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Booking file, summer 2000 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Booking file, fall 2000 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Booking file, winter 2001 (1) (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Booking file, winter 2001 (2) (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Booking file, spring 2001 (1) (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Booking file, spring 2001 (2) (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Program guides, 1997-2001 (Box 4)